<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Lifestyle &#8211; Staging Effective Altruism</title>
	<atom:link href="https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/category/lifestyle/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 22:18:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Staging100-80.png</url>
	<title>Lifestyle &#8211; Staging Effective Altruism</title>
	<link>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The judge went absolutely berserk’: my life as a barrister in badly behaved Britain</title>
		<link>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/the-judge-went-absolutely-berserk-my-life-as-a-barrister-in-badly-behaved-britain/</link>
					<comments>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/the-judge-went-absolutely-berserk-my-life-as-a-barrister-in-badly-behaved-britain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 22:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/?p=18</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I came to the end of my degree and thought: “Oh my goodness, I’ve got...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I came to the end of my degree and thought: “Oh my goodness, I’ve got to get a job. What can I do?” It was a combination of enjoying drama, theatre and public speaking, as well as spending time looking at books, that led me to train as a barrister. There are certainly lots of theatrics in court.</p>
<p>Traditionally, you never wash your wig. When you start practising, your wig is shiny and white, so it’s obvious that you are new to the job. Once you have become seasoned, your wig will be dull and beaten up, which oddly gets you more respect.</p>
<p>Court is an inherently formal environment – and the more formal the environment, the more amusing it is when someone gets something wrong. The public should refer to a high court judge as “my lord” or “my lady”, but I heard one witness use “mate”. An elderly client referred to a very dry, middle-aged judge as “young man”, which raised a snigger in the courtroom. Another guy, for reasons I never understood, called everyone “Dipper”. Outside the courtroom, he referred to me as Dipper. He referred to my client as Dipper. Then, in court, he referred to the judge as Dipper, which they found very irritating.</p>
<p>Once, the opposing client didn’t have a solicitor – which is highly unusual and not recommended – and hadn’t made any contact, so we assumed they weren’t going to turn up. Then the door burst open and in he came. The first thing the judge said was: “You haven’t produced any evidence to support your case at all. Why shouldn’t I dismiss your claim straight away?” They pulled out a plastic bag, packed full of mouldy, musky-smelling documents, and emptied it all over the judge’s desk. The judge went absolutely berserk.</p>
<p>I haven’t detected much change in people’s attitudes due to the pandemic. Sadly, human nature means just as many arguments still end up in legal disputes, although a lot of hearings are now online. This also means that people have trouble dealing with technology. One court attender couldn’t hear what was going on and got increasingly cross. He was effing and blinding that the system was rubbish, even though everyone in court could hear him. Suddenly, his son appeared in the background and said: “Dad, you’ve still got your headphones plugged in.”</p>
<p>Naturally, people are far more relaxed addressing a judge on the screen at home than they would be in court. When I called one of my witnesses to appear before the judge, she appeared on the screen in her dressing gown, looking as if she was on holiday, smoking a cigarette. I sent an urgent text message: “Can you please at least put on a jumper and put out your cigarette when you are giving your evidence?”</p>
<p>In another case, a farmer lost a litigation that resulted in him having to pay thousands of pounds to a neighbour. He went to the bank, asked for the thousands he owed in 2p coins, then mixed it into a huge pile of manure, loaded it on to a tractor, drove to his neighbours’ and tipped it all over their front garden. I had to admire his creativity.</p>
<p>The free press is under attack from multiple forces. Media outlets are closing their doors, victims to a broken business model. In much of the world, journalism is morphing into propaganda, as governments dictate what can and can’t be printed. In the last year alone, hundreds of reporters have been killed or imprisoned for doing their jobs. The UN reports that 85% of the world’s population experienced a decline in press freedom in their country in recent years.</p>
<p>As you join us today from Bangladesh we hope you will consider supporting us in our efforts to do something about this. Despite the financial challenges plaguing the media industry, we’ve decided to keep our journalism paywall-free, because we believe everyone has the right to high-quality, fact-checked reporting. And we maintain our independence thanks to generosity from readers all over the world, who understand that supporting the free press is an investment in an informed and empowered public.</p>
<p>Unlike many others, we have no billionaire owner – this helps us maintain the freedom to fearlessly chase the truth and report it with integrity. Your support will allow us to continue to work with trademark determination and passion to bring you journalism that’s always free from commercial or political interference.</p>
<p>Help power the Guardian’s reporting for the years to come, whether with a small sum or a larger one. If you can, please support us on a monthly basis from just $2. It takes less than a minute to set up, and you can rest assured that you’re making a big impact every single month in support of open, independent journalism. Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/the-judge-went-absolutely-berserk-my-life-as-a-barrister-in-badly-behaved-britain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blind date: ‘I got way too excited seeing margaritas on the menu’</title>
		<link>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/blind-date-i-got-way-too-excited-seeing-margaritas-on-the-menu/</link>
					<comments>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/blind-date-i-got-way-too-excited-seeing-margaritas-on-the-menu/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 22:17:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/?p=15</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Katie, 29, who works in television, meets Will, 35, a senior finance analyst Katie on...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Katie, 29, who works in television, meets Will, 35, a senior finance analyst</p>
<p>Katie on Will<br />
What were you hoping for?<br />
The closest I could get to being on First Dates – without making a fool of myself on television.</p>
<p>First impressions?<br />
Anyone who arrives earlier than me immediately gets a gold star.</p>
<p>What did you talk about?<br />
How we both have friend groups that organise surprise trips for each other. How Irish men are funnier and more handsome (his words). How anyone without a vice is not to be trusted.My deep fear of turning 30</p>
<p>Most awkward moment?<br />
When Will tried to take our selfie with the camera facing the wrong way. And the knowing glances from the staff throughout the evening.</p>
<p>Good table manners?<br />
Better than me! I wasn’t going to try eating pan con tomate with a knife and fork, but Will did it gracefully.</p>
<p>Best thing about Will?<br />
All those hobbies! Surfing, skiing, hiking. I don’t think I could keep up!</p>
<p>Would you introduce Will to your friends?<br />
For sure, our respective surprise-trip friend groups would have loads to discuss.</p>
<p>Describe Will in three words.<br />
Kind, adventurous and intelligent.</p>
<p>What do you think Will made of you?<br />
Way too excited at seeing margaritas on the menu.</p>
<p>Did you go on somewhere?<br />
No, I think the evening was winding down and we overstayed our welcome at the restaurant.</p>
<p>And &#8230; did you kiss?<br />
No kiss: we said goodbye on the train and the fluorescent lighting wasn’t quite the vibe.</p>
<p>If you could change one thing about the evening what would it be?<br />
It was lovely weather so a second margarita on the roof terrace before dinner wouldn’t have gone amiss …</p>
<p>Marks out of 10?<br />
8. There wasn’t that spark but I had a really fun time.</p>
<p>Would you meet again?<br />
Of course – probably as friends, it would be fun to reminisce on this experience.</p>
<p>Will on Katie<br />
Will<br />
What were you hoping for?<br />
Some fun and interesting conversation over a nice meal.</p>
<p>First impressions?<br />
Katie was very friendly with great energy.</p>
<p>What did you talk about?<br />
Spicy v non-spicy margaritas. Niche dating apps. Rainy holidays in France. Coincidently, we discovered that we had both booked holidays for mates and only revealed the destination at the airport.</p>
<p>Most awkward moment?<br />
Me failing to capture the London Eye in our rooftop selfie.</p>
<p>Good table manners?<br />
Flawless on her part. I dropped a croquette.</p>
<p>Best thing about Katie?<br />
Very easy to get along with.</p>
<p>Would you introduce Katie to your friends?<br />
Yes, she is the type of person who could get on with most people.</p>
<p>Describe Katie in three words.<br />
Fun, chatty, confident.</p>
<p>What do you think Katie made of you?<br />
We got on quite well, so nice things I hope.</p>
<p>Did you go on somewhere?<br />
No, but we spent quite a while at the restaurant.</p>
<p>Giles &amp;amp; Sarah BlindDate 2705 v2<br />
Blind date: ‘I banged my head on the table I was laughing so hard’<br />
Read more<br />
And &#8230; did you kiss?<br />
Just a hug goodbye.</p>
<p>If you could change one thing about the evening what would it be?<br />
Nothing, really, it was very pleasant. Maybe I would have ordered the churros.</p>
<p>Marks out of 10?<br />
8.</p>
<p>Would you meet again?<br />
Unfortunately not – the spark just wasn’t quite there.</p>
<p>Katie and Will ate at Aqua Nueva, London W1. Fancy a blind date? Email blind.date@theguardian.com</p>
<p>The free press is under attack from multiple forces. Media outlets are closing their doors, victims to a broken business model. In much of the world, journalism is morphing into propaganda, as governments dictate what can and can’t be printed. In the last year alone, hundreds of reporters have been killed or imprisoned for doing their jobs. The UN reports that 85% of the world’s population experienced a decline in press freedom in their country in recent years.</p>
<p>As you join us today from Bangladesh we hope you will consider supporting us in our efforts to do something about this. Despite the financial challenges plaguing the media industry, we’ve decided to keep our journalism paywall-free, because we believe everyone has the right to high-quality, fact-checked reporting. And we maintain our independence thanks to generosity from readers all over the world, who understand that supporting the free press is an investment in an informed and empowered public.</p>
<p>Unlike many others, we have no billionaire owner – this helps us maintain the freedom to fearlessly chase the truth and report it with integrity. Your support will allow us to continue to work with trademark determination and passion to bring you journalism that’s always free from commercial or political interference.</p>
<p>Help power the Guardian’s reporting for the years to come, whether with a small sum or a larger one. If you can, please support us on a monthly basis from just $2. It takes less than a minute to set up, and you can rest assured that you’re making a big impact every single month in support of open, independent journalism. Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/blind-date-i-got-way-too-excited-seeing-margaritas-on-the-menu/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
