<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Admin &#8211; Staging Effective Altruism</title>
	<atom:link href="https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/author/admin/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 22:18:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Staging100-80.png</url>
	<title>Admin &#8211; Staging Effective Altruism</title>
	<link>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The judge went absolutely berserk’: my life as a barrister in badly behaved Britain</title>
		<link>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/the-judge-went-absolutely-berserk-my-life-as-a-barrister-in-badly-behaved-britain/</link>
					<comments>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/the-judge-went-absolutely-berserk-my-life-as-a-barrister-in-badly-behaved-britain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 22:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/?p=18</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I came to the end of my degree and thought: “Oh my goodness, I’ve got...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I came to the end of my degree and thought: “Oh my goodness, I’ve got to get a job. What can I do?” It was a combination of enjoying drama, theatre and public speaking, as well as spending time looking at books, that led me to train as a barrister. There are certainly lots of theatrics in court.</p>
<p>Traditionally, you never wash your wig. When you start practising, your wig is shiny and white, so it’s obvious that you are new to the job. Once you have become seasoned, your wig will be dull and beaten up, which oddly gets you more respect.</p>
<p>Court is an inherently formal environment – and the more formal the environment, the more amusing it is when someone gets something wrong. The public should refer to a high court judge as “my lord” or “my lady”, but I heard one witness use “mate”. An elderly client referred to a very dry, middle-aged judge as “young man”, which raised a snigger in the courtroom. Another guy, for reasons I never understood, called everyone “Dipper”. Outside the courtroom, he referred to me as Dipper. He referred to my client as Dipper. Then, in court, he referred to the judge as Dipper, which they found very irritating.</p>
<p>Once, the opposing client didn’t have a solicitor – which is highly unusual and not recommended – and hadn’t made any contact, so we assumed they weren’t going to turn up. Then the door burst open and in he came. The first thing the judge said was: “You haven’t produced any evidence to support your case at all. Why shouldn’t I dismiss your claim straight away?” They pulled out a plastic bag, packed full of mouldy, musky-smelling documents, and emptied it all over the judge’s desk. The judge went absolutely berserk.</p>
<p>I haven’t detected much change in people’s attitudes due to the pandemic. Sadly, human nature means just as many arguments still end up in legal disputes, although a lot of hearings are now online. This also means that people have trouble dealing with technology. One court attender couldn’t hear what was going on and got increasingly cross. He was effing and blinding that the system was rubbish, even though everyone in court could hear him. Suddenly, his son appeared in the background and said: “Dad, you’ve still got your headphones plugged in.”</p>
<p>Naturally, people are far more relaxed addressing a judge on the screen at home than they would be in court. When I called one of my witnesses to appear before the judge, she appeared on the screen in her dressing gown, looking as if she was on holiday, smoking a cigarette. I sent an urgent text message: “Can you please at least put on a jumper and put out your cigarette when you are giving your evidence?”</p>
<p>In another case, a farmer lost a litigation that resulted in him having to pay thousands of pounds to a neighbour. He went to the bank, asked for the thousands he owed in 2p coins, then mixed it into a huge pile of manure, loaded it on to a tractor, drove to his neighbours’ and tipped it all over their front garden. I had to admire his creativity.</p>
<p>The free press is under attack from multiple forces. Media outlets are closing their doors, victims to a broken business model. In much of the world, journalism is morphing into propaganda, as governments dictate what can and can’t be printed. In the last year alone, hundreds of reporters have been killed or imprisoned for doing their jobs. The UN reports that 85% of the world’s population experienced a decline in press freedom in their country in recent years.</p>
<p>As you join us today from Bangladesh we hope you will consider supporting us in our efforts to do something about this. Despite the financial challenges plaguing the media industry, we’ve decided to keep our journalism paywall-free, because we believe everyone has the right to high-quality, fact-checked reporting. And we maintain our independence thanks to generosity from readers all over the world, who understand that supporting the free press is an investment in an informed and empowered public.</p>
<p>Unlike many others, we have no billionaire owner – this helps us maintain the freedom to fearlessly chase the truth and report it with integrity. Your support will allow us to continue to work with trademark determination and passion to bring you journalism that’s always free from commercial or political interference.</p>
<p>Help power the Guardian’s reporting for the years to come, whether with a small sum or a larger one. If you can, please support us on a monthly basis from just $2. It takes less than a minute to set up, and you can rest assured that you’re making a big impact every single month in support of open, independent journalism. Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/the-judge-went-absolutely-berserk-my-life-as-a-barrister-in-badly-behaved-britain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blind date: ‘I got way too excited seeing margaritas on the menu’</title>
		<link>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/blind-date-i-got-way-too-excited-seeing-margaritas-on-the-menu/</link>
					<comments>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/blind-date-i-got-way-too-excited-seeing-margaritas-on-the-menu/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 22:17:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/?p=15</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Katie, 29, who works in television, meets Will, 35, a senior finance analyst Katie on...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Katie, 29, who works in television, meets Will, 35, a senior finance analyst</p>
<p>Katie on Will<br />
What were you hoping for?<br />
The closest I could get to being on First Dates – without making a fool of myself on television.</p>
<p>First impressions?<br />
Anyone who arrives earlier than me immediately gets a gold star.</p>
<p>What did you talk about?<br />
How we both have friend groups that organise surprise trips for each other. How Irish men are funnier and more handsome (his words). How anyone without a vice is not to be trusted.My deep fear of turning 30</p>
<p>Most awkward moment?<br />
When Will tried to take our selfie with the camera facing the wrong way. And the knowing glances from the staff throughout the evening.</p>
<p>Good table manners?<br />
Better than me! I wasn’t going to try eating pan con tomate with a knife and fork, but Will did it gracefully.</p>
<p>Best thing about Will?<br />
All those hobbies! Surfing, skiing, hiking. I don’t think I could keep up!</p>
<p>Would you introduce Will to your friends?<br />
For sure, our respective surprise-trip friend groups would have loads to discuss.</p>
<p>Describe Will in three words.<br />
Kind, adventurous and intelligent.</p>
<p>What do you think Will made of you?<br />
Way too excited at seeing margaritas on the menu.</p>
<p>Did you go on somewhere?<br />
No, I think the evening was winding down and we overstayed our welcome at the restaurant.</p>
<p>And &#8230; did you kiss?<br />
No kiss: we said goodbye on the train and the fluorescent lighting wasn’t quite the vibe.</p>
<p>If you could change one thing about the evening what would it be?<br />
It was lovely weather so a second margarita on the roof terrace before dinner wouldn’t have gone amiss …</p>
<p>Marks out of 10?<br />
8. There wasn’t that spark but I had a really fun time.</p>
<p>Would you meet again?<br />
Of course – probably as friends, it would be fun to reminisce on this experience.</p>
<p>Will on Katie<br />
Will<br />
What were you hoping for?<br />
Some fun and interesting conversation over a nice meal.</p>
<p>First impressions?<br />
Katie was very friendly with great energy.</p>
<p>What did you talk about?<br />
Spicy v non-spicy margaritas. Niche dating apps. Rainy holidays in France. Coincidently, we discovered that we had both booked holidays for mates and only revealed the destination at the airport.</p>
<p>Most awkward moment?<br />
Me failing to capture the London Eye in our rooftop selfie.</p>
<p>Good table manners?<br />
Flawless on her part. I dropped a croquette.</p>
<p>Best thing about Katie?<br />
Very easy to get along with.</p>
<p>Would you introduce Katie to your friends?<br />
Yes, she is the type of person who could get on with most people.</p>
<p>Describe Katie in three words.<br />
Fun, chatty, confident.</p>
<p>What do you think Katie made of you?<br />
We got on quite well, so nice things I hope.</p>
<p>Did you go on somewhere?<br />
No, but we spent quite a while at the restaurant.</p>
<p>Giles &amp;amp; Sarah BlindDate 2705 v2<br />
Blind date: ‘I banged my head on the table I was laughing so hard’<br />
Read more<br />
And &#8230; did you kiss?<br />
Just a hug goodbye.</p>
<p>If you could change one thing about the evening what would it be?<br />
Nothing, really, it was very pleasant. Maybe I would have ordered the churros.</p>
<p>Marks out of 10?<br />
8.</p>
<p>Would you meet again?<br />
Unfortunately not – the spark just wasn’t quite there.</p>
<p>Katie and Will ate at Aqua Nueva, London W1. Fancy a blind date? Email blind.date@theguardian.com</p>
<p>The free press is under attack from multiple forces. Media outlets are closing their doors, victims to a broken business model. In much of the world, journalism is morphing into propaganda, as governments dictate what can and can’t be printed. In the last year alone, hundreds of reporters have been killed or imprisoned for doing their jobs. The UN reports that 85% of the world’s population experienced a decline in press freedom in their country in recent years.</p>
<p>As you join us today from Bangladesh we hope you will consider supporting us in our efforts to do something about this. Despite the financial challenges plaguing the media industry, we’ve decided to keep our journalism paywall-free, because we believe everyone has the right to high-quality, fact-checked reporting. And we maintain our independence thanks to generosity from readers all over the world, who understand that supporting the free press is an investment in an informed and empowered public.</p>
<p>Unlike many others, we have no billionaire owner – this helps us maintain the freedom to fearlessly chase the truth and report it with integrity. Your support will allow us to continue to work with trademark determination and passion to bring you journalism that’s always free from commercial or political interference.</p>
<p>Help power the Guardian’s reporting for the years to come, whether with a small sum or a larger one. If you can, please support us on a monthly basis from just $2. It takes less than a minute to set up, and you can rest assured that you’re making a big impact every single month in support of open, independent journalism. Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/blind-date-i-got-way-too-excited-seeing-margaritas-on-the-menu/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rusalka review – junk-filled staging brings magic and a sombre message</title>
		<link>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/rusalka-review-junk-filled-staging-brings-magic-and-a-sombre-message/</link>
					<comments>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/rusalka-review-junk-filled-staging-brings-magic-and-a-sombre-message/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 22:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/?p=12</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Royal Opera House, London Ann Yee and Natalie Abrahami’s thoughtful and effective new production shapes...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Royal Opera House, London<br />
Ann Yee and Natalie Abrahami’s thoughtful and effective new production shapes Dvorák’s opera into a tale of mankind versus nature. A first-rate cast is matched by Semyon Bychkov in the pit.</p>
<p>‘You’re like a vision from old fairytales,” sings the Prince to Rusalka, the doomed water-spirit heroine of Dvorák’s opera. Much in this new production by Ann Yee and Natalie Abrahami is a vision from an old opera house – in a good way. The old-fashioned feel starts with a beautifully realised aerial ballet of the Prince swimming into Rusalka’s arms and continues once the lights go up with Chloe Lamford’s sets, grand and opulent to match the richly textured orchestral playing that the conductor Semyon Bychkov is conjuring up in the pit.</p>
<p>So far, so old-school – yet some of the visual opulence is unashamed stage trickery. For Yee and Abrahami, Rusalka is about humanity versus nature, the despoiling of natural beauty by human carelessness. Their previous work together has been ecologically conscious, and that continues here: you can be impressed by the lushness of the hanging fronds around Rusalka’s lake without guessing that they are made from metres of the wardrobe department’s old offcuts.</p>
<p>Annemarie Woods’s costumes have a dressing-up-box feel, with wood spirits covered in mossy clumps and with Alexei Isaev’s Vodník entering like Lucius Malfoy dressed by Issey Miyake. Rusalka similarly wears a translucent cape, pleated from neck to toe. But as they move and the fabric catches the last-ray-before-sunset glow of Paule Constable’s lighting, we realise that they are not merely fairytale creatures emerging from the water: they are the water itself.</p>
<p>This fragile beauty can’t survive Rusalka’s move to the Prince’s palace, where she is buckled into a silver corset and everything else that’s natural is covered in gold paint or imitated in inflatable plastic. When we return to the lake in act three it’s not only Rusalka who has lost her innocence – the water is polluted, the wood spirits enraptured with the junk the Prince’s party guests have left behind.</p>
<p>Asmik Grigorian’s first Rusalka in the UK doesn’t disappoint: her polished-steel soprano glints and flashes. David Butt Philip is her outstanding match as the fickle Prince, his tenor soaring, and the rest of the cast is first-rate, from Emma Bell’s imperious yet flirty Duchess – almost the scrubbed-up twin of Sarah Connolly’s worldly-wise Ježibaba – to the comic pair of Ross Ramgobin and Hongni Wu as the forester and his nephew. All are supported at every turn by Bychkov’s wonderfully elastic and idiomatic-sounding orchestra. Yee and Abrahami may have transformed rags into riches on stage but it’s in the pit that the magic of this Rusalka really happens.</p>
<p>The free press is under attack from multiple forces. Media outlets are closing their doors, victims to a broken business model. In much of the world, journalism is morphing into propaganda, as governments dictate what can and can’t be printed. In the last year alone, hundreds of reporters have been killed or imprisoned for doing their jobs. The UN reports that 85% of the world’s population experienced a decline in press freedom in their country in recent years.</p>
<p>As you join us today from Bangladesh we hope you will consider supporting us in our efforts to do something about this. Despite the financial challenges plaguing the media industry, we’ve decided to keep our journalism paywall-free, because we believe everyone has the right to high-quality, fact-checked reporting. And we maintain our independence thanks to generosity from readers all over the world, who understand that supporting the free press is an investment in an informed and empowered public.</p>
<p>Unlike many others, we have no billionaire owner – this helps us maintain the freedom to fearlessly chase the truth and report it with integrity. Your support will allow us to continue to work with trademark determination and passion to bring you journalism that’s always free from commercial or political interference.</p>
<p>Help power the Guardian’s reporting for the years to come, whether with a small sum or a larger one. If you can, please support us on a monthly basis from just $2. It takes less than a minute to set up, and you can rest assured that you’re making a big impact every single month in support of open, independent journalism. Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/rusalka-review-junk-filled-staging-brings-magic-and-a-sombre-message/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PET/MRI an effective alternative to PET/CT for lymphoma management</title>
		<link>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/pet-mri-an-effective-alternative-to-pet-ct-for-lymphoma-management/</link>
					<comments>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/pet-mri-an-effective-alternative-to-pet-ct-for-lymphoma-management/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 22:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/?p=9</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[February 3, 2023 &#8212; With the benefit of reduced exposure to radiation, PET/MRI could become...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>February 3, 2023 &#8212; With the benefit of reduced exposure to radiation, PET/MRI could become a practical alternative to PET/CT in the routine management of lymphoma patients, according to a group of Australian researchers.</p>
<p>A team led by Dr. Vijay Mistry of Princess Alexandra Hospital in Brisbane compared the diagnostic performance of same-day FDG-PET/MRI versus FDG-PET/CT in patients with newly diagnosed Hodgkin and non-Hodgkin lymphoma. The approaches matched almost perfectly, yet the group gave PET/MRI the edge given that it exposed patients to less radiation.</p>
<p>&#8220;With high concordance in disease site identification, staging, and response assessment, PET/MRI is a potentially viable alternative to PET/CT in lymphoma that minimizes radiation exposure,&#8221; the team wrote. The study was published online January 24 in Cancer Imaging.</p>
<p>Accurate staging and treatment response assessment are essential for patients with lymphoma. FDG-PET/CT scans are widely used, with FDG radiotracer standardized uptake values providing scores clinicians use to detect changes in tumors. But lymphoma patients diagnosed typically require multiple imaging examinations over the course of diagnosis, treatment, and surveillance. Considering the potential impact of radiation exposure, imaging approaches using MRI are of clinical interest, the authors wrote.</p>
<p>Mistry and colleagues explored the use of a hybrid PET/MRI imaging system in these patients, comparing its performance to FDG-PET/CT scans. They conducted a study that included 50 adult patients with a new diagnosis of any subtype of lymphoma. Patients underwent same-day PET/MRI following PET/CT for staging purposes using the same F-18 FDG injection. All patients were also invited to undergo a PET/MRI after PET/CT scans at interim and end-of-treatment assessments.</p>
<p>A 20-year-old male with biopsy-proven classical Hodgkin lymphoma, stage IVB. Baseline PET/ CT (a-c) and baseline PET/MR (d-e). At interim restaging PET/CT (f–h) and PET/MR (i-k), there was a concordant complete metabolic response, Deauville 2. The end of treatment study is not shown as there remained complete metabolic response. Incidental right-sided rib fractures persisted between staging and interim studies. SUV scale set between 0-8. Image courtesy of Cancer Imaging through CC BY 4.0.<br />
At staging, PET/CT detected 352 positive disease sites out of a potential 1,500 sites across 50 patients. PET/MRI detected 339 out of 352 true-positive sites, 1,148 true-negative sites, and 13 false-negatives sites. There was excellent intermodality agreement between PET/MRI and PET/CT, the researchers reported (k = 0.976, p &lt; 0.001). There was also good correlation of disease site identification at interim assessment (k = 0.819, p &lt; 0.001) and excellent correlation at end-of-treatment assessment (k = 1, p &lt; 0.001), they reported.</p>
<p>Another benefit of PET/MRI? Lower patient effective dose (ED): ED for PET/CT was 10.5 mSv per scan, while the average calculated ED for the PET/MR was 4.8 mV per scan, resulting in a difference of 5.7 mSv dose decrease (54%) between the two modalities.</p>
<p>&#8220;With the benefit of avoiding radiation exposure, PET/MRI appears an attractive alternative to PET/CT across indolent and aggressive lymphomas with comparable performance,&#8221; the authors wrote.</p>
<p>Ultimately, PET/CT is the current standard in imaging of lymphoma patients due to availability and familiarity. This study supports the introduction of PET/MRI into clinical practice, yet further research on its diagnostic performance is crucial, the team noted.</p>
<p>&#8220;Given the contemporary nature of PET/MRI, studies with multiple institutions with standardized imaging protocols would allow further assessment of inter-equipment variability and would benefit from a larger recruitment population,&#8221; Mistry and colleagues concluded.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/pet-mri-an-effective-alternative-to-pet-ct-for-lymphoma-management/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will Virtual Staging Help Sell Your Home?</title>
		<link>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/will-virtual-staging-help-sell-your-home/</link>
					<comments>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/will-virtual-staging-help-sell-your-home/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 22:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/?p=6</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When a real estate agent lists a home, staging is a big part of the...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When a real estate agent lists a home, staging is a big part of the prep work before the property is ready to be presented to the world. Some degree of staging has become commonplace, especially in the more competitive markets around the country. Typically, a Realtor will work with the furniture and decor already in the home, adding, removing or rearranging various pieces to showcase the space best.</p>
<p>But if the seller has already moved out or the seller’s taste proves challenging to the sale, the listing agent may advise the seller to rent or buy curated furniture and decor for staging purposes. Since this can be costly, virtual staging can be used instead, wherein three-dimensional furniture and home accessories are digitally added to the listing photos.</p>
<p>Read: Types of Roads That Can Have a Big Impact on Home Sales<br />
Why Would You Virtually Stage a Property?<br />
In recent years, with the proliferation of design-themed TV and an explosion of new development in diverse markets across the country, many buyers have lost the ability to imagine their own furnishings in an empty space or to see past a homeowner’s bad taste. Our eyes have been trained for years by staged and neutrally decorated homes that look eerily similar to one another, no matter the city or price point.</p>
<p>In order to appeal to a wide audience and also compete with newly built homes, the resale market has followed suit, and many properties come to market as stripped-down versions of what they were, eliminating extreme colors, the seller’s personality, dated home decor, and indications of wear and tear whenever possible.</p>
<p>Although sellers and their agents may go to great lengths to do all this, sometimes there isn’t enough time or budget to furnish an empty space or redecorate an ugly one. In these cases, virtual staging is a viable option to grab the attention of internet surfers and motivate potential buyers to click instead of scrolling to the next listing.</p>
<p>“Virtual staging is a cost-effective method for staging a property and has become increasingly popular in markets where homes are selling quickly,” says Georgina Jacobson, a real estate agent with Coldwell Banker in Newport Beach, California. She notes that one of the main benefits of using virtual staging versus actual staging is the quick turnaround, since actual furniture doesn’t need to be moved in or out.</p>
<p>Furthermore, virtual staging allows for the creative and imaginative implementation of furnishings that can make a property seem simultaneously luxurious, aspirational and inviting in a way that might not be doable in real life.</p>
<p>How Does Virtual Staging Help Sell an Empty Property?<br />
In the case of a vacant property, after the photos of the empty rooms have been taken, some services can digitally place three-dimensional furniture and decor into the property pictures. The marketing photos with digital furnishings help potential buyers to envision what the space might look like with attractive and aspirational decor, staged like model homes have been for years, as opposed to being presented empty and thus potentially reading as lifeless. The added furniture also adds perspective to the photo, giving the viewer’s eye a place to land and better understand the scale of a room.</p>
<p>The vast majority of real estate searches start online, and when buyers are scrolling through listings, they may look at the lead photo for mere seconds before deciding if they want to click. An empty room doesn’t get clicks like furnished (or digitally furnished) homes do.</p>
<p>“It really does make a difference when people are scrolling,” says Felicia Captain, a real estate agent with Coldwell Banker Realty in Wellesley, Massachusetts. “They are more inclined to continue viewing the photos of virtually staged rooms rather than empty spaces, especially in new construction homes,” she notes.</p>
<p>Although many buyers are great at visualizing the potential of a space, many just aren’t, and they need some help to see potential instead of seeing an empty space. “I find it is super helpful for buyers to visualize the potential of a room and understand how they can use the room to suit their specific needs,” Captain says. “It provides an aesthetic for the space that perhaps they can relate to or see themselves living in.”</p>
<p>Jacobson adds, “Virtually staged listings help buyers to get a better feel for an otherwise empty space prior to seeing it in person. It is difficult for a buyer to have an understanding of the room if there is no furniture in it. Virtual staging also can serve as a source of inspiration for how they could furnish the property themselves.”</p>
<p>Read: How Does Selling a House As-Is Work?<br />
How Does Virtual Staging Help Sell an Ugly Property?<br />
Virtual staging can also mask dated or ugly design choices that might otherwise make a potential buyer swipe left. “Listing a property with dated or unattractive furniture and decor can be a major turnoff for buyers, as it does not give them a good first impression of the property,” Jacobson says. In these cases, virtual staging can showcase what could be, instead of the less appealing reality of what is.</p>
<p>“Virtual staging is a useful tool when a current owner’s aesthetic might be a hindrance to attracting showing appointments, especially since photos are the first thing buyers assess before setting up a showing,” says Jodi D. Levy, a real estate agent and co-owner of Grand Lux Realty in Chappaqua, New York. As technology has improved, ugly colors on walls or cabinets, dated furniture and even clutter can be digitally erased and replaced with a more contemporary or upscale look.</p>
<p>A new home represents a new chapter in someone’s life, perhaps fulfilling a dream, and it can be difficult for buyers to visually remove someone else’s belongings and fantasize about their own. Virtually staging a dated property with neutral but elegant furnishings can help shape the aspirational fantasy in a buyer’s mind.</p>
<p>What Are the Pitfalls to Avoid in Virtual Staging?<br />
Just as real estate agents should strive for marketing materials to be high quality, so too should virtual staging – low-quality marketing of any kind can imply a low-quality home. If three-dimensional furnishings in a marketing photo look too pixelated or obviously fake, this can be a turnoff to prospective buyers.</p>
<p>Conversely, if the virtual staging is too good, buyers might feel misled upon seeing the property in real life. “It’s important to be transparent and disclose when using virtual staging,” Levy says.</p>
<p>As helpful as virtual staging can be for prospective buyers to visualize the potential for an empty or badly decorated space, many agents will alternate the photos in the marketing, with the un-doctored photos right behind the clearly labeled “virtually staged” photos. “For some prospective buyers, seeing a space without furniture is extremely helpful, but others need the visual assistance,” Levy says.</p>
<p>Given that virtual staging has become somewhat commonplace, many buyers are accustomed to seeing it used. “As long as virtual staging is properly disclosed, I don&#8217;t believe it is misleading to prospective buyers,” Jacobson says. “We never want buyers to be unpleasantly surprised when they see a property in person.”</p>
<p>And when there might be an infinite number of design options to pluck from a digital library, the choices should be carefully considered. “The style and design of the virtual staging should align with the property,” Captain says. “I try to use a style that fits the architectural design of the property while adding contemporary and transitional features for today&#8217;s living preferences.”</p>
<p>Read: The Guide to Understanding Your Home Value.<br />
While the doctored photos might be helpful to buyers when scrolling through online listings, they can also be useful in the actual home, especially in empty rooms. Propping up an easel in the property with a blown-up copy of the virtually staged photo is a great way to showcase what could be. Captain notes that “having large photo canvases of the virtually staged rooms is helpful, so the prospective buyer sees the virtual staging in a larger format while standing in the space.”</p>
<p>As our culture becomes increasingly visually oriented regarding how we process products marketed to us, first impressions can make or break a sale, especially in competitive real estate markets. Property photos are usually the first thing that prospective buyers come across, and these photos have to grab the attention of web surfers before they scroll to the next listing. When photos of empty or ugly rooms fail to engage the viewer, virtual staging is a valuable marketing asset.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://staging.effectivealtruism.org/will-virtual-staging-help-sell-your-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
